<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Quiz</string>
    <string name="random">What Makes an Excellent Professor?

The best professors treat students like people, not numbers, they go beyond their call of
duty in terms of helping students and holding office hours; they not only know their material,
but they also know how to teach it well.
They understand the student and concernsthe class may have
a great professor must also be defined in terms of quality of research done, involvement in the campus community,
quality of teaching, and other important criteria.

1. Good Teachers Are Strong Communicators.
it comes to effective teaching, strong communication skills are a must.

“I’m a firm believer in communication in all forms,” “As a leader, communication is a tool for overcoming fear.”

2. Good Teachers Listen Well.

Great communication doesnt stop when the teacher is done talking. Listening well is one of the most important skills needed to be a teacher.

“Teachers that are skilled in listening and observing often pick up on what isn’t being said, such as any anxieties a student may have, and can then help the student build their skills and confidence levels," said student Kristine Ducote, who is earning her bachelor's in criminal justice.

Student Latricia Maddox, who is studying for a bachelor's in business, said that effective listening skills also help a teacher better understand their students and tailor lessons to reach them how they learn best.

“If an educator can truly hear a student, they can learn how to reach them where they are,” she said. “This will open the door for them to receive and learn the lesson that is being taught.”

Good Teachers Focus on Collaboration.
Latricia Maddox with the text Latricia Maddox
Working in education means you’re never truly working alone. From paraprofessionals and teaching assistants to other classroom teachers and school leaders, working as a teacher often means working effectively in a group. It's also important to keep an open mind and learn from other educators.

The key to success in this kind of environment, Tanguay said, is the ability to collaborate. "You really need to be able to fill various roles in order to collaborate effectively," he said. "If you already have someone on your team who is going to be the one to critique all of the suggestions made, then you don\'t need to join in on that. Instead, maybe you need to be the person who is going to come up with creative ideas. You need to have that flexibility."

Good Teachers Are Adaptable.
Dr. Audrey Rogers with the text Dr. Audrey Rogers
Effective teachers need to be able to work in a constantly evolving environment and adjust their teaching methods based on the age of their students, the resources available and changing curriculum, practices and requirements.

As a teacher since the 1980s, SNHU education professor and on campus undergraduate program chairman Dr. Audrey Rogers said she’s seen tremendous changes in the education field throughout her career, particularly with the rise in access to the internet, computers and other technology. What is teaching going to look like in another 30 years? The only thing certain, Rogers said, is change.

“Change is a constant,” she said. “Learning how to adapt and adjust, that’s been one of the skills that’s been most helpful in my career. It’s about keeping my finger on the pulse of who my students are over time and all the trends, standards and new research, and being able to continually improve.”

Adaptability is also one of the key skills needed to be a teacher who may be educating students of varying grade levels or different learning styles, Tanguay said.

“You have to be able to adapt based upon your audience,” he said.

Good Teachers Are Engaging.
Being able to engage students with humor, creative lessons and a strong classroom presence is an important part of what makes someone a good teacher, Tanguay said.

“If you were to envision that teacher that you would want in your life, even now, you’re going to want someone who is very engaging in front of the classroom,” he said. “A good teacher will perform for their students to keep them going... It’s not about sitting back and just lecturing, it’s about engaging in the work.”

What an engaging teacher looks like will vary depending on grade level and subject matter, Tanguay said.

In kindergarten, an engaging teacher might be one who gets down on the floor to do activities with their students on their level. In high school, an engaging teacher may be one who thinks outside the box, adds humor to their lessons and finds creative ways to bring learning into the real world.

Some Teachers and proffesors that have made an impact:

1-Albert Einstein

2-Nicola Tesla

3-Stephen Hawking

4-Thomas Edison

5-Issac Newton

6-Prof. Samer Hanna

7-Charles Darwin

8-Alan Turing


Good Teachers Show Empathy.
Another key to engaging students and improving their learning is to treat each student as an individual, by being empathetic and understanding to what may be going on in their lives, Tanguay said.

“We need to take a moment to think back and think about what could be going on in this student’s life,” he said. “It’s so important to be observant, attentive, empathetic and always have a positive attitude.”

No matter where your career path takes you – whether to an elementary school, secondary school or even to the university level – your teaching can have a profound impact on the lives of students, and your education is the foundation for that work.

“Teachers make such a huge impact on their students’ lives,” said student Donna Whisman, who is earning her bachelor's in communication. “I believe that being a teacher is a very special gift, and those that have that gift make a positive, lasting impression on the lives of their students that can totally change the trajectory of their lives.”
</string>
</resources>